Guide to the Yale University Art Gallery Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Art Gallery records
1832-1962
RU 487
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
(3 boxes and 1 16mm film can)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, letters, lists, bulletins, a register, memorabilia, a 16mm film and financial materials documenting the Yale Art Gallery and art at Yale.
Yale University. Art Gallery
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 33-B (YRG 33-B), Records of the Yale Art Gallery.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, letters, lists, bulletins, a register, memorabilia, a 16mm film and financial materials documenting the Yale Art Gallery and art at Yale.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Art museums; Art; College art museums; Trumbull, John, 1756-1843; Yale University -- Museums; Yale University. Art Gallery; Yale University. Gallery of Fine Arts
- Financial records, register, and memorabilia, circa 1832- 1866; Accession 19ND-A-147
  - Financial records, 1832-1862 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Guest register, 1863-1866 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Labels from frames of miniatures by John Trumbull, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Trumbull seal, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Records, 1926-1962; Accession 1983-A-001
  - Associates in Fine Arts at Yale University
    - General, 1926-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
    - Bulletin, Copyright of, 1931-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Drive, New Members, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 10)
    - Financial Reports, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Payment of Dues, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chicago, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - St. Louis, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Trustees, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Chicago Trustees, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - New York Trustees, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters Asking for Money Towards Building Fund; Some Answers and Acknowledgments, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Letters in Answer to CHS Plea for Building Fund Donations - Trustees, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Building Fund
    - General, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence with Executive Committee of Associates, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence with Philip Goodwin, 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (T. Sizer etc.), 1930-1946 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Gifts, 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 25 - 26)
    - Prospective Donor Lists, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gallery Affairs, Printed Material
    - General Matters, not Associates or Sales Desk, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Gallery Attendance Records, 1928-1958 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bulletin, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Corner-Stone Laying Ceremony, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "The New Collegiate Architecture at Yale", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "Yale's New School of Art and Architecture", undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "A Guide to the Collections", Accession 2000-A-070
  - "A Guide to the Collections" (Box 1)
- "This is the Second Show", Accession 2012-A-079
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - "This is the Second Show" Art Gallery film; Alumni collections, 1961; 1 (Box 1)